A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, News Releases FA745
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, News Releases
1948-1995
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA745
7 Cubic Feet 14 boxes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for scholarly research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Scope and Contents
Ford Foundation News and press releases.
Ford Foundation
- News Releases, volume 1, 1948 December 20 - 1953 February 26; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Study Committee announced, 1948 December 20 (Box 1)
  - Henry Ford Hospital grant, 1950 February 23 (Box 1)
  - Grants in scientific research in human behavior and national administration, 1950 September 30 (Box 1)
  - Chester C. Davis and Robert M. Hutchins appointed as associate directors, 1950 December 19 (Box 1)
  - George F. Kennan appointment as consultant, 1951 February 19 (Box 1)
  - H. Rowan Gather Jr. appointed as associate director, 1951 February 22 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation - December 31, 1950 financial statement, 1951 March 23 (Box 1)
  - James Webb Young appointed as consultant in communications, 1951 April 2 (Box 1)
  - International Press Institute establishment, 1951 April 16 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) established, 1951 April 19 (Box 1)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE) established, 1951 April 23 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) fellowship program, 1951 April 26 (Box 1)
  - Alvin C. Eurich appointed as Vice President of the Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE), 1951 May 16 (Box 1)
  - Free Russia Fund, Inc. established - George F. Kennan, President, 1951 May 17 (Box 1)
  - Free Russia Fund, Inc. grants, 1951 May 31 (Box 1)
  - Oliver May appointed as Secretary and Treasurer, 1951 June 7 (Box 1)
  - Behavioral Sciences program - Bernard Berelson senior staff officer, 1951 June 27 (Box 1)
  - Milton Katz appointed as associate director, 1951 June 28 (Box 1)
  - Pre-Induction Scholarship Program, 1951 July 15 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education - Faculty Fellowships, 1951 July 19 (Box 1)
  - Free Russia Fund, Inc. - Research Program on the USSR, 1951 July 23 (Box 1)
  - Economic resources overseas grants - worldwide study trip, including Europe, India, and Pakistan, 1951 August 1 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop established, 1951 August 6 (Box 1)
  - Robert M. Hutchins speech at Free University of Berlin, Germany, 1951 August 6 (Box 1)
  - Robert Saudek appointed to Director of TV-Radio Workshop, 1951 August 14 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Fox and Ernest Perry appointed as Assistant Treasurers, 1951 August 21 (Box 1)
  - Paul Hoffman return from Europe and Asia study trip, 1951 August 24 (Box 1)
  - Public announcements of grants made by the Ford Foundation and Funds in 1951, 1951 September 4 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund, Inc. grants, 1951 October 25 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Sixth United Nations General Assembly, Paris, 1951 October 31 (Box 1)
  - E.J.B. Rose named Director of the international Press Institute, 1951 November 14 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) Faculty Fellowships, 1951 November 15 (Box 1)
  - George F. Kennan resignation from East European Fund, 1951 November 24 (Box 1)
  - Carl B. Spaeth to assist overseas activities of the Ford Foundation, 1951 December 11 (Box 1)
  - Edward F. Eubanks appointed as Assistant Information Officer, 1952 January 8 (Box 1)
  - Richard M. Bissell Jr. joins staff of the Ford Foundation, 1952 January 29 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees meeting, 1952 February 2 (Box 1)
  - India and Pakistan projects announced, 1952 February 4 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees meeting, 1952 February 8 (Box 1)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE) grants in educational television and radio, 1952 February 19 (Box 1)
  - Milton Katz speech, Pomona College, 1952 March 13 (Box 1)
  - Melville J. Ruggles appointed as Director of the East European Fund, Inc., 1952 March 16 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) Faculty Fellowship Program for 1952-1953 school year, 1952 April 1 (Box 1)
  - Board of Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) established, Gordon Gray - Chairman, 1952 March 24 (Box 1)
  - Edwin G. Arnold joins the Ford Foundation's New York staff, 1952 April (Box 1)
  - "Perspectives USA" announced, 1952 April 7 (Box 1)
  - $1.8 million grant to Government of India announced, 1952 April 19 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation representatives visit Middle Eastern nations, 1952 May 12 (Box 1)
  - Oslo Institute for Social Research grant announced, 1952 May 15 (Box 1)
  - Intercultural relations grants, Robert Redfield, University of Chicago, 1952 May 19 (Box 1)
  - Educational television and radio grants, 1952 May 20 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) program for self-studies of liberal arts colleges, 1952 June 10 (Box 1)
  - "The People Act" radio series, 1952 June23 (Box 1)
  - Social science grants to University of Chicago, Columbia university, Harvard university, University of Minnesota, 1952 June 27 (Box 1)
  - Indian agricultural officials visit United States on two month study trip, 1952 Summer (Box 1)
  - James Webb Young resignation, 1952 June 30 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus, 1952 July 2 (Box 1)
  - Indian agricultural officials visit United States on two month study trip, 1952 August (Box 1)
  - Program of the Special Study in the United States of Extension Principles, organization and Methods by Extension Service Directors from India, 1952 August (Box 1)
  - Jack Perlis - Omnibus publicity, 1952 August 4 (Box 1)
  - United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees - refugees in Europe - G.J. van Heuven Goedhart, 1952 August 4 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus, 1952 August 14 (Box 1)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE) grants, 1952 September 8 (Box 1)
  - New international review to publish high-level American culture overseas - "Perspectives USA", 1952 September 15 (Box 1)
  - Omnibus - William Saroyan plays, 1952 September 24 (Box 1)
  - William Spier - TV-Radio Workshop, Omnibus, 1952 September 24 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus - "Mr. Lincoln" series, 1952 October 1 (Box 1)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) Foreign Study and Research Fellowships awarded, 1952 October 6 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund scholarships to Ukrainian undergraduates - soviet exiles, 1952 October 9 (Box 1)
  - Donald A. Lowrie, Director of East European Fund, 1952 October 13 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus sponsorship by Willys-Overland Motors Inc., 1952 October 15 (Box 1)
  - Indian agricultural officials end two month visit to United States, 1952 October 19 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) Faculty Fellowships, 1952 October 26 (Box 1)
  - Cleon O. Swayzee appointed as Director of Research for the Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR), 1952 November 3 (Box 1)
  - Experiment in video programming - The objectives and aims of "Omnibus", by Robert Saudek, 1952 November 9 (Box 1)
  - Alistair Cooke joins Omnibus, 1952 November 9 (Box 1)
  - Randall T. Kleme appointed as representative for Pakistan, 1952 November 10 (Box 1)
  - Grants to scholars in human behavior research, 1952 November 14 (Box 1)
  - Charles E. Wyzanski Jr. elected to Board of Trustees, 1952 November 18 (Box 1)
  - Milton Katz - American Association for the United Nations speech, 1952 November 18 (Box 1)
  - Near East grants - Carl Spaeth, 1952 November 24 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Study and Research Fellowship Program, 1952 November 30 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Republic established, 1952 December 13 (Box 1)
  - George M. Humphrey resignation from Board of the Fund for Adult Education, 1952 December 17 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund - Research Program on the USSR projects published, 1952 December 28 (Box 1)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE) - purpose and operating principles, 1953 January 16 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus, Metropolitan Opera Company, "Die Fledermaus", 1953 January 21 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus - Remington Rand Inc.'s sponsorship, 1953 January 22 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund grants and annual report, 1953 January 25 (Box 1)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences appropriation of $3.5 million, Board appointed, 1953 February 1 (Box 1)
  - Transfer of Ford Foundation offices from Pasadena to New York, 1953 February 4 (Box 1)
  - H. Rowan Gaither Jr. appointed President of the Ford Foundation, 1953 February 5 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus, Cellini Cup of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1953 February 10 (Box 1)
  - American paintings exhibited in India, 1953 February 15 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop - Omnibus, Metropolitan Opera Company, "La Boheme", 1953 February 17 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund scholarships to soviet exiles, 1953 February (Box 1)
  - David C. Munford appointed to Director of the East European Fund, 1953 February 24 (Box 1)
  - $15 million grant to the Fund for the Republic, 1953 February 26 (Box 1)
- News Releases, volume 2, 1953 March 11 - 1955 December 12; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 1)
  - Intercultural Publications Inc. President James Laughlin (New Directions) receives Legion of Honor award, 1953 March 11 (Box 1)
  - H. Rowan Gaither Jr. letter to Rep. Donald L. Jackson (R-California), 1953 March 17 (Box 1)
  - Owen J. Roberts elected to Chairman, Board of Directors, the Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE), 1953 April 15 (Box 1)
  - Review of grants in the Near East, 1953 April 17 (Box 1)
  - George Bernard Shaw plays presented on Omnibus, 1953 April 20 (Box 1)
  - Paul H. Durrie joins the Fund for Adult Education (FAE), 1953 April 29 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) Faculty Fellowships, 1953 April 30 (Box 1)
  - Horace Albright elected to Chairman, and R.G. Gustavson elected to President of Resources for the Future, Inc., 1953 May 2 (Box 1)
  - Omnibus returns to CBS, 1953 May 12 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) program for self-studies of liberal arts colleges continued, 1953 May 15 (Box 1)
  - Frederick Lewis Allen and James F. Brownlee elected to Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 1953 May 15 (Box 1)
  - Junior Omnibus to debut on NBC, 1953 May 19 (Box 1)
  - Rep. Clifford P. Case (R-New Jersey) elected to President of the Fund for the Republic, 1953 May 26 (Box 1)
  - Elmer A. Starch appointed Ford Foundation representative in Indonesia, 1953 May 27 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Report - Summary statement for editors, 1953 June 1 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) fellowships for high school teachers, 1953 June 3 (Box 1)
  - Research Program on the USSR - publication of "The Northern Seas Route: Its place in Russian Economic History Before 1917", 1953 June 7 (Box 1)
  - "Bridging the Gap Between School and College" report published by The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE), 1953 June 14 (Box 1)
  - Ralph W. Tyler named Director of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1953 June 15 (Box 1)
  - Three sponsors for Omnibus, 1953 June 17 (Box 1)
  - Grants for self-surveys of American universities' research program in behavioral sciences, 1953 June 21 (Box 1)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) Foreign Study and Research Fellowships awarded - second series, 1953 June 22 (Box 1)
  - Burgess Meredith signed for "Junior Omnibus", 1953 June 24 (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian-English dictionary, C.H. Andrusyshen - East European Fund, 1953 June 25 (Box 1)
  - Robert H. Knapp joins Behavioral Sciences Division of the Ford Foundation, 1953 June 26 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for Adult Education study grants program announced, 1953 June 28 (Box 1)
  - John J. McCloy elected to Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, Chester C. Davis resignation, 1953 June 1 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop, Omnibus principal executives, 1953 July 1 (Box 1)
  - Jerry Staff named Producer of "Junior Omnibus" program, 1953 July 1 (Box 1)
  - Producer and two directors named for Omnibus program, 1953 July 1 (Box 1)
  - "Soviet Economic Policy in Postwar Germany" published - Research Program on the USSR, 1953 July 5 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) - "Emergency Recruitment and Teacher Education Project", Los Angeles, 1953 July 15 (Box 1)
  - Behavioral Sciences Division grants since January 1952, 1953 July 20 (Box 1)
  - Thomas H. Carroll II joins the Ford Foundation, 1953 July 26 (Box 1)
  - Behavioral Sciences Division report, 1953 August 9 (Box 1)
  - Behavioral Sciences Division exchange program grants, 1953 August 26 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop, "Excursion" program, appearances and negotiations with Presidents Truman and Hoover, 1953 September 3 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop, "Excursion" program to premier, 1953 September 6 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Annual Report released, 1953 September 18 (Box 1)
  - Merritt W. Barnum named producer of "Excursion" program, 1953 September 22 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop, Omnibus to premier October 4, 1953 on CBS, 1953 September 23 (Box 1)
  - George F. Kennan elected to East European Fund's Board of Trustees, 1953 September 24 (Box 1)
  - President Herbert Hoover to appear on "Excursion" program, TV-Radio Workshop, 1953 September 25 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for Adult Education (FAE), "The Challenge of Lifetime Learning", second annual report announced, 1953 September 27 (Box 1)
  - Chester C. Davis study of India's farm credit problems, 1953 September 29 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund scholarships to soviet exiles, 1953 October 4 (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus" to present Orson Welles in "King Lear", 1953 October 13 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop advisory board announced, 1953 October 19 (Box 1)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) fellowships for study and research in Asia and the Middle East, Near East, 1953 October 26 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for Adult Education (FAE), grants, 1953 November 9 (Box 1)
  - Horace Holmes appointed as consultant on foreign village development, 1953 November 15 (Box 1)
  - Jack Benny to appear in comedy fantasy on "Omnibus", 1953 November 24 (Box 1)
  - "Perspectives USA" edited by Malcolm Cowley, 1953 December (Box 1)
  - The Fund for Adult Education (FAE) study awards, scholarships, and fellowships, 1953 December 1 (Box 1)
  - Board on Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) scholarships and fellowships for study on Soviet and East European areas, 1953 December 7 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) national fellowship program for high school teachers, 1953 December 13 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) self-surveys of colleges and universities, 1953 December 15 (Box 1)
  - East European Fund second annual report - soviet refugees, 1953 December 21 (Box 1)
  - Milton Katz appointed as Program Counsellor, 1954 January 14 (Box 1)
  - Milton Katz appointed as Director of International Legal Studies at Harvard University, 1954 January 14 (Box 1)
  - "Perspectives USA" edited by R.P. Blackmur, 1954 February (Box 1)
  - East European Fund Inc. - Chekov Publishing House grant, 1954 February 15 (Box 1)
  - $25 million grant to the Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE), 1954 February 20 (Box 1)
  - TV-Radio Workshop appropriation for the 1954-1955 season, 1954 February 27 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for Adult Education (FAE) study awards, scholarships, and fellowships, 1954 March 1 (Box 1)
  - Mark F. Etheridge and Laurence M. Gould elected to Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 1954 April 4 (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus", third season to begin October 17, 1954, TV-Radio Workshop, 1954 April 5 (Box 1)
  - Fellowships in behavioral sciences, 1954 April 30 (Box 1)
  - "Perspectives USA" number 7 announced, 1954 May 3 (Box 1)
  - The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) fellowships to college and university faculty, 1954 May 21 (Box 1)
  - Resignation of Robert M. Hutchins as Associate Director, 1954 May 25 (Box 1)
  - Robert M. Hutchins elected to President of the Fund for the Republic, 1954 May 25 (Box 1)
  - Southern Education Reporting Service established, 1954 May 30 (Box 1)
  - Rowland Egger appointed as Near East representative in Beirut, Lebanon, 1954 June 10 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation grant to Resources for the Future, 1954 June 20 (Box 1)
  - Fred Allen to appear on "Omnibus", 1954 September 29 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Study and Research Fellowship competition for academic year 1955-1956 announced, 1954 October 10 (Box 1)
  - Finance Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1954 October 21 (Box 1)
  - "The First Community Leadership Institute of the Fund for Adult Education" conference, 1954 November (Box 1)
  - John Osman appointed Acting Eastern Regional Representative of the Fund for Adult Education (FAE), 1954 November 2 (Box 1)
  - Robert Redfield, anthropologist, named to Fund for Adult Education (FAE) lectureship, 1954 November 13 (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus" to present "The Merry Widow" by Franz Lehar, 1954 December 6 (Box 1)
  - Statement of H. Rowan Gaither Jr. regarding the Reece Committee (U.S. Congress), 1954 December 20 (Box 1)
  - Grants to four law schools to assist development of international legal studies, 1955 January 10 (Box 1)
  - Harvard University news release on Law School's program of International Legal Studies, 1955 January 10 (Box 1)
  - Columbia University news release on Law School, and international legal studies, 1955 January 10 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Law School news release on international legal studies, 1955 January 10 (Box 1)
  - Stanford University School of Law news release on international legal studies, 1955 January 10 (Box 1)
  - Grant to School of Law of the University of California at Berkeley to Assist Development of International Legal Studies, 1955 January 23 (Box 1)
  - University of California, Berkeley - School of Law news release on international legal studies, 1955 January 23 (Box 1)
  - $50 million appropriated to raise faculty salaries of private colleges and universities, 1955 March 7 (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus" to offer experimental play; Jack Dempsey and Martha Scott in cast, 1955 March (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus" offers experimental treatment of "The Iliad", 1955 March 28 (Box 1)
  - Authentic music and dance from India with comment by Yehudi Menuhin, television version of classic American novel featured on "Omnibus", 1955 April 3 (Box 1)
  - Behavioral sciences fellowships for the 1955-1956 academic year, 1955 April 25 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation announces fellowships for African Study, 1955 May 9 (Box 1)
  - Finance Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1955 May 10 (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus" returns to CBS, 1955 May 13 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation announces fellowships for Asian and Near Eastern Study, 1955 May 25 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation's "Report for 1954" issued, 1955 May 30 (Box 1)
  - Foreign Area Study Fellowships for the 1956-1957 academic year, 1955 June 6 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation names fellows for studies of USSR and Eastern Europe, 1955 June 6 (Box 1)
  - George F. Gant appointed as Ford Foundation representative in Pakistan, 1955 June 15 (Box 1)
  - Lloyd G. Reynolds appointed Director of Economic Development and Administration (EDA) program, 1955 June 15 (Box 1)
  - Quigg Newton Jr. appointed Director of the Public Affairs (PA) program, 1955 June 17 (Box 1)
  - Committee to advise the $50 million appropriation to raise faculty salaries at private colleges and universities, 1955 June 20 (Box 1)
  - F.F. Hill elected to Vice President for Overseas Development program, 1955 July 31 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation announces International Relations Fellowships, 1955 August 22 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly meeting of the Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 1955 October 1 (Box 1)
  - "Omnibus" presents "The Birth of Modern Times", 1955 October 3 (Box 1)
  - F.F. Hill assumes Ford Foundation Vice Presidency, 1955 October 17 (Box 1)
  - Donald K. David appointed Chairman of the Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1955 October 20 (Box 1)
  - Statement by Trustees of the Ford Foundation [Ford Motor Company stock, and diversification of the Ford Foundation's investment portfolio], 1955 November 6 (Box 1)
  - The Ford Foundation and the American Enterprise System, address by H. Rowan Gaither Jr. before the Economic Club of Detroit, 1955 November 7 (Box 1)
  - Statement by H. Rowan Gaither Jr. [Public offering of Ford Motor Company stock], 1955 November 9 (Box 1)
  - Quigg Newton Jr. elected to Vice President, 1955 November 23 (Box 1)
  - Julius Stratton elected to Board of Trustees, 1955 December 10 (Box 1)
  - $500 million appropriation for privately supported institutions (colleges, universities, hospitals, medical schools), 1955 December 12 (Box 1)
- News Releases, volume 3, 1955 December 12 - 1956 May 3; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 2)
- News Releases, volume 4, 1956 May 8 - 1957 March 10; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 2)
- News Releases, volume 5, 1957 March 15 - 1957 July 9; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 3)
- News Releases, volume 6, 1957 August 1 - 1959 May 25; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 3)
- News Releases, volume 7, 1959 June 2 - 1960 July 20; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 4)
- News Releases, volume 8, 1960 August 1 - 1961 June 26; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 4)
- News Releases, volume 9, 1961 July 5 - 1962 September 14; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 5)
- News Releases, volume 10, 1962 October 10 - 1964 April 9; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 5)
- News Releases, volume 11, 1964 April 9 - 1965 December 30; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 6)
- News Releases, volume 12, 1966 January 3 - 1966 December 16; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 6)
- News Releases, volume 13, 1967 January 3 - 1967 December 29; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 7)
- News Releases, volume 14, 1968 January 3 - 1968 September 29; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 7)
- News Releases, volume 15, 1968 October 4 - 1969 June 24; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 8)
- News Releases, volume 16, 1969 July 8 - 1970 September 22; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 8)
- News Releases, volume 17, 1970 October 1 - 1971 September 28; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 9)
- News Releases, volume 18, 1971 September 28 - 1972 December 26; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 9)
- News Releases, volume 19, 1973 January 9 - 1974 January 7; 1 Bound Volumes (Box 9)
  - ‘Research in Contraception and Reproduction: A Status Report, 1973’ article published in the journal Family Planning Perspectives, 1974 January 7 (Box 9)
  - Greek arts, letters, and sciences, 1974 January 3 (Box 9)
  - Disposition of remaining Ford Motor Company stock, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Appointments of Peter de Janosi, officer in charge, Office of Higher Education and Research, and James T. Ivy, assistant to the Vice President for Administration and officer in charge of Logistical Services, 1973 (Box 9)
  - ‘Ford Foundation Letter’ Special Report: The Real World of Lawyering, 1973 December 15 (Box 9)
  - “Minorities and Public Television: An Appraisal”, by the Advisory Panel on Minorities and Public Television, 1973 October (Box 9)
  - 26 Grants for research on population issues announced, Rockefeller Foundation and Ford Foundation, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Marshall A. Robinson appointed Vice President, Office of Resources and the Environment, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Robert H. Edwards named head of Middle East and Africa office, 1973 (Box 9)
  - C. Fred Bergsten, Brookings Institution study, “Future of the International Economic order: An Agenda for Research”, 1973 October 22 (Box 9)
  - Testimony of Harold Howe II to the Education Subcommittee of the United States Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, 1973 October 17 (Box 9)
  - International Center for Tropical Agriculture (CIAT) formal dedication, 1973 October 3 (Box 9)